# CHRISTOPHE BLANC

M E C H A T R O N I C S E N G I N E E R

## **PROFILE**

I am a mechatronics engineer with three years of experience in industrial robotics in the aeronautics field. I am a recent graduate of an apprenticeship which enabled me to consolidated my multi-disciplinary cursus.

Today, I am looking to move into a career in the field of neural engineering.

I am seeking an international environment of innovation and research.

### **CORE COMPETENCIES**

Mechanical engineering Electrical engineering MBSE Multiphysics simulation Systems engineering, V&V Materials science Industrial robotics

## **LANGUAGES**

French: native language

English : fluent

Spanish : intermediate Japanese : beginner

### **CONTACT DETAILS**

**Phone**: +33.610.501.890

**E-mail**: christophe.blanc@mines-ales.org

**LinkedIn**: https://www.linkedin.com/in/chris-blanc/ **Adress**: 3 bis impasse du mistral, 34430 Saint Jean

de Védas, France

### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

## **Mechatronic engineer apprentice**

CIMPA, September 2018 - October 2021

- Analysis of different CAM solutions for Airbus, benchmark of the whole manufacturing scope
- Post-processors development for industrial robots in Airbus' plants
- Industrial robotics innovation use-cases for salon du Bourget

## Production and manufacturing planning technician

POMA. May 2018 - August 2018

- Lean manufacturing application
- Mounting ranges
- Tools CAD design

## **ACADEMIC BACKGROUND**

### **IMT Mines Ales**

Master's Degree in Engineering | September 2018 - September 2021

National diploma in mechatronic engineering, multidisciplinary background in mechanics, electronics and programming

- Advanced skills in systems engineering and multiphysics project management
- 3-year project of a sampling rover in a deactivated nuclear cell with production of a prototype.

## **Troyes institute of technology**

Mechanical engineering associate's degree | September 2016 - August 2018

- Design, manufacturing and simulation
- Algebra and physics
- Academic mobile robot project

## **EXTERNAL LINKS**

### Some pictures of my final year project :

https://drive.google.com/drive/folders/1c7M61I0MouTl7d8qk9jva8IhQZKqv1XS?usp=sharing

### My engineering school:

https://www.mines-ales.fr/en/node/254